# Jeremy Smith

## Software Engineer

**07398722784** @ jeremyrrsmith@gmail.com

## ♥ London or Bristol

#### **PERSONAL SUMMARY**

An experienced professional with 5 years experience in financial advice and 10 years experience in property.

I was introduced to coding 20+ years ago, as a computer gaming child that soldered circuit boards at a/s electronics classes and who played with code for fun, but my career took me on another path.

I am looking to get into software development so that I can be creative, solve problems, make friends and be in touch with the latest technologies.

#### **CODING PROJECTS**

## Online Marketplace

A tech test: with promotional discounts being provided on items in the basket of the checkout. Promotions are separate and can be applied to different items over different terms and in combination.

- This was a TDD'd project with modules, and nice object encapsulation.
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Online-marketplace

## Acebook: A Facebook Clone

A group project collaboratively working to create a clone of Facebook.

- · Deployed here: https://acebook-business-logic.herokuapp.com/
- Daily stand-ups, retros, working with a kanban board to manage tasks in an agile manner, TDD'ing branches to merge to master after peer review
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/acebook-business-logic

## Bowling scorecard challenge

A repo containing my solution to the common bowling scorecard kata.

- This used test driven development with mocking, objects, refactoring, and modelling all on Github with fairly tidy SOLID code.
- https://github.com/JRRS1982/bowling\_scorecard\_v2

#### Boris Bikes: A Ruby program

A simple project used to train good development attributes.

- An encapsulated, test driven, object oriented Ruby program.
- Tidy code, with good test coverage, nice commit messages and hopefully a demonstration of some good practice.
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Boris-Bike/tree/master/Boris\_Bikes

#### **Bank Tech Test**

A typical tech test: I have used here to demonstrate best practice

- This used test driven development with mocking, objects, refactoring, and modelling all on Github with fairly tidy commit messages.
- % https://github.com/JRRS1982/Bank\_Tech\_Test



#### **SKILLS**



#### **EDUCATION**

## Software Development Bootcamp

#### **Makers Academy**

- Intensive coding bootcamp.
- Front and backend software development / web development.

#### Post Grad Diploma Real Estate

#### University of Kingston

**(1)** 09/2007 - 07/2009 **♥** Kingston, UK

A part time distance course completed while in full time employment.

## Business Admin. B.A. (hons)

## Plymouth University

· Course rep for three years

#### TRAINING / COURSES

Freecode Camp - responsive web design, HTML, CSS and Javascript

**Udemy - Comprehensive Ruby Programming** and RSpec courses.

Sololearn - Ruby pathway

Exorcism - Ruby / Javascript pathways.

Many 'meetups' on various subjects

## Personal notes on coding languages / best practice

A nested table of my notes on best practice.

https://www.notion.so/Best-Practice-Language-notes-3a8dfb1bec6c49f0 987d5dd5a544c18b

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Wealth Management Assistant

**Close Brothers** 

**1** 07/2017 - 01/2019

♥ Liverpool Street, London.

Providing support to private clients by advising them what to invest in and how to better manage their money by doing it for them.

- Appointed as the London representative on the companies 'business improvement forum'.
- I was specifically selected for and by the top billing advisor in the company.

#### Sales Consultant

**AMPP Group** 

With UK and Indian governmental support I contacted C-Suite management in global multinational companies and objection handled gatekeepers to book appointments between the CEO and my director.

• I arranged the target number of calls but did not like the 'hotbox' culture.

## Wealth Management Assistant

**Thomas Miller** 

**1** 03/2016 - 04/2017

Q City, London

A fantastic and friendly wealth management / investment department that provided advice to private clients and managed their investments.

- · I helped in the development of a new CRM system
- · I sat in client meetings, solved multiple administrative process issues with clients advice and the investment team reporting.

## Client Service Executive

Foster Denovo

**1** 05/2014 - 03/2016

**♀** City, London

A financial advice company

On top of daily responsibilities I restructured client management spreadsheets, which led to the release of many unprofitable clients, and discovering additional income for the advisors.

## Team Leader (Initial Market Report Team)

Countrywide Corporate ## 08/2010 - 03/2014

♥ Weybridge, Surrey

A property repossession and then sales company.

- I managed the team through it's relocation from Weybridge to Bracknell, during my time at the helm of this team of 10 we had the lowest staff turnover in the company.
- Promoted into management after demonstrating my work ethic.

#### **PASSIONS**

Cooking for / with friends



Always be learning something new



Countryside trips



Reading



**Festivals** 



Cycling / Camping / Wild Swimming



Altruism

#### FIND MF ONLINE



#### Gihub

https://github.com/JRRS1982/CV



## Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeremysmith-2b3a9b15/



#### **Twitter**

@leremystwita